# Joshua Wilson

Versatile software developer with 7+ years of experience working with small teams and building killer applications with especially deep knowledge of building tools and services in Python 2.7, MongoDB, and AngularJS. I've worked in the scientific, financial, and now web services sectors. Always looking for a new challenge. @wilsojb is my handle on many services.

Brooklyn, NY (919) 323-6369 wilsojb@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/wilsojb wilsojb.me

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# Mobile Developer, TripExpert, NYC

NOV 2015 - PRESENT

I am developing an app for iOS and Android built using Cordova, AngularJS, and the Ionic framework that complements tripexpert.com.

## Operations Engineer, Hudson River Trading, NYC

APRIL 2011 - SEPT 2015

Was a member of a tight-knit team responsible for monitoring market conditions, connectivity, and all continuously deployed internal systems. Working on a new feature, debugging legacy software, reviewing a pile of pull requests, and dealing with a market outage were all in a day's work. I also played an active role in their hiring, training, and documentation efforts.

I spent most of my time developing internal tools in Python, Perl, and Bash and played an integral role in converting a legacy code base into a library of tools used company-wide. Part of that involved meeting with other engineers and business teams on a regular basis to discuss requirements, but mostly it meant banging out high-quality work as fast as possible. I helped define and steward technical standards and implemented a test-driven development lifecycle. I was also responsible for administering and scaling a MongoDB replica set.

## Research Assistant, University of North Carolina, NC

DEC 2008 - DEC 2010

Physics student finds a home in the Department of Physical Oceanography and studied numerical fluid dynamics there for a few years. All of my code from this period is published on github (http://wilsojb.io/pdelab). I had the opportunity to collect data on a ship in the Massachusetts Bay for two weeks at sea. It was a blast.

### LANGUAGES (+ dbs + fwks )

**Fluent** in Python, Perl, Bash, MongoDB, and AngularJS.

Working knowledge of Linux, Ionic, HTML/CSS, Cordova, MySQL, Git/SVN, SciPy, TCP/IP, and FIX.

I'm also familiar with C++, jQuery, Node.js, Go, Redis, and Java.

**%E** atom, sublime, emacs, Sketch, and :q in vi

#### A LITTLE EXTRA

Backpacking is my favorite mode of transportation. I've done it through Europe, India, and Southeast Asia (so far). I love snowboarding and hiking and really anything outdoors. I'm a to-do list geek, a crontab nerd, and enjoy cooking big, elaborate meals for my friends and family. I'm always in the middle of 2-3 books and enjoy fixing the 1999 Jeep Cherokee that I share with my girlfriend.

My complete work history can be found at linkedin.com/in/wilsojb

#### **EDUCATION**

## University of North Carolina, Chapel Hill, NC

M.S. in Physics, December 2010

My emphasis was in numerical modeling and culminated with the publication of **Numerical Approximations to the Boussinesq Equations** (http://bit.ly/10GfzIn)

## Hendrix College, Conway, AR

B.A in Physics w/ minor in Computer Science, May 2008

I presented twice at the American Physical Society's annual conference. Here a the links to the abstracts: Laser Assisted Cancer Immunotherapy: Surface Irradiation (http://bit.ly/1kmwHWZ) and Construction and Calibration of a Six Degree of Freedom Thrust Sensor (http://bit.ly/1RlYpo4).

#### **OPEN SOURCE**

## **Pdelab**

http://wilsojb.io/pdelab

An object oriented framework for solving and analyzing PDEs. This project grew organically while I worked on my graduate degree. The goal of the framework was to abstract away the mechanics and other "lower level" code needed to solve PDEs so the researcher can spend more time focusing on their solver (i.e. their "business logic").